# ION MINTER Currently located in Mindrand, M... (240) 604-7999 | IAM@JONMINTER.DEV | https://www.jonminter.dev

# **ABOUT MF**

Talented, creative, and highly motivated Software Engineer with over a decade of proven technical ability and leadership. Expertise in data processing pipelines, APIs, microservices and building systems in the cloud. Derives satisfaction from solving complex problems with technology. Primarily seeking remote roles but open to relocation for the right opportunity.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Stripe, Remote (MI)

Infrastructure Engineer | Jul 2021 - Nov 2022

- Building a real-time analytics platform for Stripe engineers across the company on top of Apache Pinot
- Leading effort to build a control plane to automate operations of Apache Pinot clusters

# 540, Crystal City VA

Principal Engineer | Nov 2019 - Jul 2021

- Lead team of 8 engineers helping the US Army modernize and take their financial systems to the cloud
- Scaled up team when taking on new clients/work by working with the CTO to determine hiring needs, create interview loops, and evaluate candidates

# Capital One, McLean VA

Senior Software Engineer | Jul 2018 - Nov 2019

- Worked on data pipeline that processed/enriched the clickstream data from all customer facing mobile and web applications
- Worked on mission critical authorization platform automating infrastructure maintenance/deploys, improving performance and reducing infrastructure costs and engineering time needed to maintain the system

# 540, Crystal City VA

Senior Software Engineer | Nov 2015 - Jul 2018

- Built data processing pipeline and APIs for the FDIC to automate a manual data cleanup and delivery process and improve the UX for consumers of FDIC datasets
- Built and maintained website to help procurement specialists in the government manage and share procurement information
- Provided architecture and devops consulting for other teams in the company

# Lockheed Martin, Crystal City VA

Senior Web Applications Developer | Jun 2015 - Nov 2015

 Built web application for the GSA to connect acquisition specialists throughout the government and provide a system for them to better track and manage the acquisition process

# Computer Technology Consulting, Windermere FL

Senior Developer | Apr 2012 - Jun 2015

 Maintained systems for customer that sold theme park tickets, event tickets, and hotel reservations

# Walt Disney Parks and Resorts Online, Celebration FL

Senior Web Developer | Feb 2011 - Mar 2012

• Helped build new version of DisneyWorld.com as part of Disney's effort to revamp the theme park infrastructure and introduce Disney's FastPass

# NBC/Universal, Remote (FL)

Consultant/Software Engineer | Oct 2010 - Apr 2013

- Updated services that powered the search feature on NBC.com to use Apache Solr as a backend and remove dependency on legacy backend no longer supported by vendor and add search autocomplete functionality
- Created content management system that was used to manage the content for TV shows on NBC.com

# Bonnier Corporation, Winter Park FL

Senior Developer | Feb 2009 - Feb 2011

 Helped create core Drupal infrastructure/modules used by all Drupal applications powering websites for magazines published by Bonnier

# Entertainment Benefits Group, Lake Buena Vista FL

Senior Programmer/Analyst | Apr 2007 - Feb 2009

 Made many improvements to the infrastructure/web applications such as implementing automated credit card payment processing, automated inventory purchasing with vendors such as Disney World & Broadway, and enabling horizontal scaling of the services powering the web applications allowing the systems to scale with growth of business

# **EDUCATION**

# University of Maryland, College Park MD

Studied Computer Science | Sep 2005 - Dec 2006

# Prince George's Community College, Largo MD

A.S. Computer Science | Sep 2002 - May 2005